Guide to the Jane Roberts Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1972-1974; Accession 2001-M-058
  - Jane Roberts' ESP class sessions
    - 1973 August 21, 28, CD #26; 1 (Box 28)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 28U)
    - 1973 September 11, CD #27; 1 (Box 29)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 29U)
    - 1973 September 18, 25 October 2, CD #28A; 1 (Box 30)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 30U)
    - 1973 October 2, 9, 16, 30, November 6, CD #28B/29; 1 (Box 31)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 31U)
    - 1973 December 4, 11, 18, CD #30/31; 1 (Box 32)
      - 1 use copy (Box 32U)
    - 1973 December 18, 1974 January 3, CD #31 (continued); 1 (Box 33)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 33U)
    - 1974 January 8, 15, 22, CD #32; 1 (Box 34)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 34U)
    - 1974 January 22, 29, February 5, CD #33; 1 (Box 35)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 35U)
    - 1974 February 5, 12, CD #34; 1 (Box 36)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 36U)
    - 1974 February 19, CD #35; 1 (Box 37)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 37U)
    - 1974 February 19, 26 and March 12, 19, 26, CD #35 (continued)/36 (begin); 1 (Box 38)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 38U)
    - 1974 March 26, CD #36 (continued); 1 (Box 39)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 39U)
    - 1974 April 2, 9, 16, CD #37; 1 (Box 40)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 40U)
    - 1974 April 16, 23, May 7, CD #37 (continued); 1 (Box 41)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 41U)
    - 1974 May 14, 21, 28, CD #38; 1 (Box 42)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 42U)
    - 1975 May 28, June 4, 11, CD #38 (continued)/39 (begin); 1 (Box 43)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 43U)
    - 1974 June 4, 11, 18, CD #39 (continued)/40 (begin); 1 (Box 44)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 44U)
    - 1974 June 25, CD #40 (continued); 1 (Box 45)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 45U)
    - 1974 July 9, 16, CD #41; 1 (Box 46)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 46U)
    - 1974 July 16, CD #42; 1 (Box 47)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 47U)
- Additional material, Circa 1999; Accession 2001-M-063
  Received from Sue Watkins, 2001.
  - Conversations with Seth: the Story of Jane Roberts's ESP Class, by Susan Watkins [various drafts, boxed in the order received, Circa 1999 (Box 1–2)
    Various drafts, arranged in the order received. See also revised volumes I and II of this publication in Accession 2001-M-049.
- Additional material, 1973-1991; Accession 2002-M-014
  Received from Madelon Rose Logue, 2001.
  - Correspondence of Orville G. Tigerman with Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1973-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and printed materials pertaining to Seth presentations and seminars conducted by Seth Group members Orville G. Tigerman, Charles A. Hauck, and Harlan A. Smith, 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Additional material, 1972-1974; Accession 2002-M-015
  These tapes may duplicate audiocassette tapes in the original accession (Boxes 7a-7q, 8a-8q, 9a-9q, 10a-10p, and 11a-11p). Tape numbers on the reel-to-reel tapes in this accession were transcribed from the original boxes. Dates of tapes included in this inventory were transcribed from the original boxes; when no date exists in the inventory, there was none on the box to transcribe. The tapes in this accession were originally recorded by Don Hall. According to a researcher, some of these reel-to-reel tapes were used by Richard Kendall to create the audiocassettes in Accession 1998-M-079. The compact discs (and use copies) in Accession 2001-M-058 possibly duplicate the contents of the reel-to-reel tapes in this accession and the Kendall audiocassettes in Accession 1998-M-079.
  Received from Mary Rouen, Brass Ring Bookstore (Eugene, OR), 2001.
  - Reel-to-reel tapes of ESP class sessions taught by Jane Roberts
    - 1972 October 3, Tape 2; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    - 1972 October 10, Tape 3; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
    - 1972 October 17, Tape 4; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
    - 1972 October 31, November 7, Tape 5; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 4)
    - 1972 November 14, 21, 28, Tape 6A; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
    - 1972 December 5, 12, Tape 7; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 6)
    - 1972 December 5, 12, Tape 7A; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 7)
    - 1972 December 19, Tape 8; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 8)
    - 1973 January 9, Tape 9; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - 1972 December 19, 1973 January 9, Tape 10; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 10)
      Tape quality is poor, with variable speeds and noise.
    - 1973 January 9, Tape 10A; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 11)
    - 1973 January 16, 23, Tape 11; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 12)
    - 1973 January 16, Tape 11A; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 13)
      One side of tape is unintelligible and other side is blank.
    - 1973 January 23, Tape 11B; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 14)
    - 1973 January 30, Tape 12; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 15)
    - 1973 February 6, Tape 13; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 16)
    - 1973 February 13, 20, 27, Tape 14; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 17)
      Middle part of tape is very fuzzy (muffled?).
    - Undated, Tape 15; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 18)
    - Undated, Tape 16; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 19)
    - Undated, Tape 17; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 20)
    - Undated, Tape 18; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 21)
    - Undated, Tape 18A; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 22)
    - Undated, Tape 19; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 23)
      Very fuzzy static throughout first half of tape.
    - Undated, Tape 20; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 24)
    - Undated, Tape 21; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 25)
    - 1973 May 15, Tape 22; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 26)
    - Undated, Tape 23; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 27)
    - Undated, Tape 24A; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 28)
      Tape broken.
    - Undated, Tape 24B; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 29)
    - Undated, Tape 25A; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 30)
    - Undated, Tape 25B; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 31)
    - Undated, Tape 26; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 32)
    - Undated, Tape 27 I; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 33)
    - Undated, Tape 27 II; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 34)
    - Undated, Tape 28 I; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 35)
    - Undated, Tape 28 II; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 36)
    - Undated, Tape 29; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 37)
    - Undated, Tape 30 I; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 38)
      Note on box says tape is blank.
    - Undated, Tape 30 II; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 39)
    - Undated, Tape 31; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 40)
    - 1974 January 22, Tape 32; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 41)
    - 1974 January 29, February 5, Tape 33; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 42)
    - 1974 February 5, 12, 19, Tape 34; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 43)
    - 1974 February 19, 26, March 5, Tape 35; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 44)
    - 1974 March 12, 19, 26, Tape 36; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 45)
    - 1974 April 2, 9, 16, 23, 30, May 7, Tape 37; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 46)
    - 1974 May 14, 21, 28, Tape 38; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 47)
    - 1974 June 4, 11, Tape 39; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 48)
    - 1974 June 18, 25, July 2, Tape 40; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 49)
    - 1974 July 9, 16, Tape 41; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 50)
    - Undated, Tape 42; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 51)
- Additional material, 1973-1974; Accession 2002-M-016
  Received from Mary Dillman, 2001.
  - Transcript of special session pertaining to language, requested by William Kautz, 1973 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Summary of Remarks" by Jane Roberts pertaining to an informal session with William Kautz, 1974 November 24
    - Typed transcript (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Recording of remarks, 3 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 2–4)
      - Use copies, 3 compact discs (Audio CD) (Box 2U–4U)
- Additional material, 1999-2001; Accession 2002-M-027
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 2001.
  Researchers wishing to use the fan mail in Accession 2002-M-027 must sign an "Access agreement for the fan mail in the Jane Roberts Papers" in order to be given access to this material.
  Includes Accession 2002-M-045. Comprises Jane Roberts fan mail listed chronologically. Accompanying audiotapes and printed materials are filed after the fan mail. Fan mail is also contained in Accessions 1985-M-014 and 2003-M-029.
  - Fan mail
    - 1999 December-2001 March (Box 1)
    - 2001 November-December (Box 2)
  - Printed materials and audiovisual items that accompanied fan mail, 2000 January-2001 December (Box 2)
- Additional material, 1935-1963; Accession 2002-M-028
  - Photocopies of newspaper clippings pertaining to Jane Roberts, Robert F. Butts, Jr., and family members, 1935-1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional material, 1993-1996; Accession 2002-M-071
  Received from Madelon Rose Logue, 2002.
  - Hummingbird Home: Biological Spirituality Newsletter, contains "Seth Says" column, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    This accession comprises the following issues of the publication: winter 1993-1994, spring 1994, autumn 1995, and summer 1996.
- Additional material, Circa 1990s; Accession 2002-M-085
  Received from Joyce L. Combs, 2002.
  - "Seth Says," deck of playing cards containing quotes from various Seth Books, Circa 1990s (Reel 1)
- Additional material, 1997-2002; Accession 2002-M-086
  One issue (2002 March) received from Robert F. Butts (Accession 2002-M-086), 2002. Received from Mike Flynn (Accession 2002-M-100), 2002.
  Includes Accession 2002-M-100.
  - Writings on the Wall: A Journal of Self-Empowerment
    Publication contains references to Jane Roberts and Seth; published monthly.
    - 1997 January-December (Box 1)
    - 1998 January-October (Box 1)
    - 1999 January-December (Box 1)
    - 2000 January-December (Box 2)
    - 2001 February-December (Box 2)
    - 2002 January-June (Box 2)
- Additional material, 2000-2006; Accession 2002-M-087
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 2002, 2006.
  Includes Accessions 2002-M-101 and 2010-M-034.
  - Photocopies of artwork by Robert F. Butts, Jr.
    - Drawings of a friend and a self-portrait in the 1800s, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Self-portrait, in oil, in 1800s, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Additional artwork, 2000-2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 2002; Accession 2002-M-103
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 2002.
  - Die Natur der Persönlichen Realität, by Jane Roberts, 2002 (Box 1)
  - La Naturaleza de la Realidad Personal, by Jane Roberts [Habla Seth III], 2002 (Box 1)
  - An introduction by Robert F. Butts, Jr. to the Portuguese translation of The Nature of Personal Reality, 2002 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 2002-2003; Accession 2003-M-012
  Received from Lucy Gillis, 2002-2003.
  Includes Accession 2003-M-059.
  - The Lucid Dream Exchange, no. 23 and no. 26, 2002 Jun, 2003 March (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1981, 1991-2002; Accession 2003-M-029
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 2002-2003
  Researchers wishing to use the fan mail in Accession 2003-M-029 must sign an "Access agreement for the fan mail in the Jane Roberts Papers" in order to be given access to this material.
  Includes Accessions 2003-M-043, 2003-M-074, 2003-M-080, and 2004-M-002. Comprises Jane Roberts fan mail listed chronologically. Accompanying audiotapes are listed after the fan mail, also in chronological order. Fan mail is also contained in Accessions 1985-M-014 and 2002-M-027.
  - Fan mail
    - 1981 February 5 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1991 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1992 October-December (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 13)
    - 1994 January (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1995 Apr, Jun, Nov, December (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Includes responses from Robert F. Butts, Jr.
    - 1996 January-May, Jul, Sep, Oct, December (Box 1, Folder 16 - 17)
    - 1997 January-May, July-December (Box 1, Folder 18 - 19)
    - 1998 January-May (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 2000 September 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 2001 January-December (Box 1, Folder 22 - 23)
    - 2002 January-December 10 (Box 1, Folder 24 - 27)
    - 2002 December 11-31 (Box 2, Folder 28 - 29)
    - 2003 Jan, Mar, April (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Audiovisual materials
    - 1993 July (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Includes accompanying correspondence.
    - 2000 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - 2002 July (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - 2002 December (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Additional material, 1970-1979; Accession 2004-M-087
  The tapes from which these compact discs were made were originally recorded by a variety of people. These compact discs fill in the missing dates of compact discs in Accession 2001-M-058.
  Received from Mary Dillman, 2004.
  Original computer discs, as well as preservation masters, are may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies.
  - ESP class sessions taught by Jane Roberts
    - 1970 November 3, 24, CD #1; 1 (Box 1)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 1U)
    - 1970 December 1, CD #2; 1 (Box 2)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 2U)
    - 1970 December 1 [continued], 1971 January 5, 12, CD #3; 1 (Box 3)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 3U)
    - 1971 January 19, May 18, CD #4; 1 (Box 4)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 4U)
    - 1971 July 6, 27, CD #5; 1 (Box 5)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 5U)
    - 1971 August 31, CD #6; 1 (Box 6)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 6U)
    - 1971 September 7, 1972 March 7, 21, CD #7; 1 (Box 7)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 7U)
    - 1972 March 28, April 4, CD #8; 1 (Box 8)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 8U)
    - 1972 April 11, 18, CD #9; 1 (Box 9)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 9U)
    - 1972 April 25, May 2, 9, CD #10; 1 (Box 10)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 10U)
    - 1972 May 16, CD #11; 1 (Box 11)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 11U)
    - 1972 May 23, CD #12; 1 (Box 12)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 12U)
    - 1972 May 30, June 6, 13, CD #13; 1 (Box 13)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 13U)
    - 1972 June 20, July 18, CD #14; 1 (Box 14)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 14U)
    - 1972 July 25, August 1, CD #15; 1 (Box 15)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 15U)
    - 1972 August 22, CD #16; 1 (Box 16)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 16U)
    - 1972 August 29, CD #17; 1 (Box 17)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 17U)
    - 1972 September 5, CD #18; 1 (Box 18)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 18U)
    - 1972 September 12, CD #19; 1 (Box 19)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 19U)
    - 1972 September 19, CD #20; 1 (Box 20)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 20U)
    - 1972 October 24, 1973 January 16, CD #21; 1 (Box 21)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 21U)
    - 1973 March 6, May 29, June 12, CD #22; 1 (Box 22)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 22U)
    - 1973 July 3, 10, CD #23; 1 (Box 23)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 23U)
    - 1973 July 31, September 4, CD #24; 1 (Box 24)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 24U)
    - 1973 October 23, November 13, CD #25; 1 (Box 25)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 25U)
    - 1974 March 5, July 2, CD #26; 1 (Box 26)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 26U)
    - 1975 June 6, CD #27; 1 (Box 27)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 27U)
    - 1975 June 6 [continued], CD #28; 1 (Box 28)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 28U)
    - 1975 July 12, CD #29; 1 (Box 29)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 29U)
    - 1975 July 12 [continued], CD #30; 1 (Box 30)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 30U)
    - 1975 August 16, 1977 April 8, CD #31; 1 (Box 31)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 31U)
    - 1978 December 2, CD #32; 1 (Box 32)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 32U)
    - 1978 December 2 [continued], CD #33; 1 (Box 33)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 33U)
    - 1978 December 2 [continued], CD #34; 1 (Box 34)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 34U)
    - 1979 September 29, CD #35; 1 (Box 35)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 35U)
- Additional material, 1982-2005; Accession 2006-M-079
  Received from Madelon Rose Logue, 2006.
  This accession consists of correspondence and related materials sent to Madelon Rose Logue, editor and publisher of Black Sheep, the Seth/Jane Roberts fanzine, primarily by Robert F. Butts, Jr.
  - Correspondence
    - Butts, Laurel to Madelon Rose Logue, 1982-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Butts, Jr., Robert F. to Madelon Rose Logue, 1984-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2-7)
    - Watkins, Susan and Peter Danison to Madelon Rose Logue, 1989-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Others to Madelon Rose Logue, 1984-2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Responses of Madelon Rose Logue to Robert and Laurel Butts, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Responses of Madelon Rose Logue to Susan Watkins and Peter Danison, 1989, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Form letters as responses by Jane Roberts to correspondents
    - General, 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Tigerman, Orville, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Photographs from Sethnet Conference, Elmira, New York, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Additional material, 1976-1981; Accession 2006-M-110
  Received from Mary Rouen, 2006.
  This accession consists of prints of paintings done by Jane Roberts. They are listed alphabetically by title.
  - "The Fence Outside My Writing Room", 1981 April (Box 1)
  - "A Gift of Flowers From A Friend", 1988 September (Box 1)
  - "Looking South From Our Hill House", 1976 October (Box 1)
  - "My Fantastic Tree of Life", 1977 July (Box 1)
  - "My Husband's Bouquet For Me", 1981 (Box 1)
  - "A Room In Our Hill House", 1977 February (Box 1)
  - "A Vase Rob and I Have Loved For Years", 1977 March (Box 1)
  - "A Winter View From Our Hill House", 1978 (Box 1)
- Additional material, Circa 1979-1981; Accession 2007-M-024
  Received from Sabine Lucas, 2006.
  This accession consists of correspondence to Sabine Lucas, a German Jungian psychologist who translated Seth material into German.
  - Butts, Jr., Robert F., 1979 October 22, November 6 (Box 1)
  - Roberts, Jane, Circa 1979-1981 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1985-1988; Accession 2012-M-016
  Received from Tam Mossman, 2011.
  - Correspondence between literary agent Tam Mossman and Robert F. Butts and Laurel Davies
    - 1985 Jul-1986 Dec (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1987 Mar-1988 Jan (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Individual Versus Society: Conflict on a Symbolic Battlefront", Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Annotated typescript (pages 71-79), presumably written by Tam Mossman.
- Additional material, 1987; Accession 2012-M-029
  Received from Jeff King, 2011.
  - "The Little Artificial Christmas Tree," by Jane Roberts, 1987 (Box 1)
    An eight-page typed document copyrighted in 1987 by Robert F. Butts. An earlier 1976 version in box 30 of the original accession is handwritten and includes drawings.
    See also: box 30
- Additional material, circa 2017; Accession 2018-M-0023
  This accession includes photocopies of stories by Jane Roberts previously published in Black Sheep. Stories include First Communion, Nightmare, The Big Freeze, Three Times Around, A Demon at Devotions, The Red Wagon, and Impasse.
  - Stories, circa 2017 (Box 1)